A Guide to the Commonwealth Fund records, Improving Health Care Services Program, SG 2, Series 7 FA786
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund records, Improving Health Care Services Program, SG 2, Series 7
1992-1997
Rockefeller Archive Center
Commonwealth Fund
FA786
5.7 Cubic Feet 15 letter document boxes.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research with select materials restricted as noted. Brittle or damaged items are available at the discretion of RAC.
Researchers interested in accessing digital media (floppy disks, CDs, DVDs, etc.) or audiovisual material (audio cassettes, VHS, etc.) in this collection must use an access surrogate. The original items may not be accessed because of preservation concerns. To request an access surrogate be made, or if you are unsure if there is an access surrogate, please contact an archivist.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Commonwealth Fund records were donated to RAC in 1985. Record transfers began in 1986, and accruals continue.
Arrangement
As received.
Scope and Contents
This series primarily contains program staff files documenting pertinent grants, surveys, symposiums, issue papers, and Commission on Women's Health activities.
- Commonwealth Fund records, Improving Health Care Services Program, 1992-1997; 7
  - Harvard University - Maine's Health Care Delivery System: A Model for Change (Grant 93-76), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harvard University - Maine's Health Care Delivery System: A Model for Change (Grant 93-76) - Administration, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Harvard University - Maine's Health Care Delivery System: A Model for Change (Grant 93-76) - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Harvard University - Maine's Health Care Delivery System: A Model for Change (Grant 93-76) - Article and Background Material (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Harvard University - Maine's Health Care Delivery System: A Model for Change (Grant 93-76) - Grant Products, 1993-1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 94-08), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 94-08) - Advisory Committee Meeting, 1993 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 94-08) - Grant Products, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 94-08), 1993-1997 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 94-08) - Elizabeth McCaughey Debate, 1994 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Columbia University School of Public Health - Medicaid Managed Care in New York City (Grant 94-10) - Administration, 1993-1997 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Columbia University School of Public Health - Medicaid Managed Care in New York City (Grant 94-10) - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Columbia University School of Public Health - Medicaid Managed Care in New York City (Grant 94-10) - Readings, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Columbia University School of Public Health - Medicaid Managed Care in New York City (Grant 94-10) - Grant Products, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
  - Columbia University School of Public Health - Medicaid Managed Care in New York City (Grant 94-10) - Grant Products, 1993-1995 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - University of California-San Francisco (Grant 94-60) - Final Report - Evaluating Health Care Reform in Select States, 1996 February (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 95-06), 1994-1997 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - University of Massachusetts-Amherst - Schoen - Support for the Administration of the Health Care Reform Program (Grant 95-06), 1994-1997 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Maine Health Care Reform Commission (Grant 95-43), 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Maine Health Care Reform Commission (Grant 95-43) - Grant Products, 1994-1996 (Box 4, Folder 21-23)
  - Maine Health Care Reform Commission (Grant 95-43) - Grant Products, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Grantmakers in Health - McDermott - Quality and Accountability in Managed Care (Grant 96641), 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Grantmakers in Health - McDermott - Quality and Accountability in Managed Care (Grant 96641) - Grant Products, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Health Care Coverage and Access Program - Support for Program Direction (Grant 970948), 1995-1998 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Women's Health and Managed Care Presentations, 1993-1995 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Women's Health and Managed Care Presentations, 1993-1995 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Women's Health Program Overview, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Completed Grant Reports Meeting, 1996-1997 (Box 6, Folder 31-32)
  - Women's Health Survey - Quarterly Insert, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Commission on Women's Health (Grant 94-45), 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Commission on Women's Health (Grant 94-45) - Correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 35-36)
  - Commission on Women's Health (Grant 94-45) - Reports, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Karen Davis - Presentations, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Background - Domestic Violence, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Background and Launch, 1993-1994 (Box 8, Folder 40-41)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Meeting 1, 1993 September 22 (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Planning and Launch, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Planning - Members, 1992-1993 (Box 8, Folder 44)
    Conditions Governing Access
    Restricted from scholarly access - Open in 2023.
  - Commission on Women's Health - Members, 1993 (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Women's Health Initiative - Board Meeting Presentations, 1992 November 10 (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Women's Health - Meetings, 1993 June (Box 9, Folder 47-48)
  - Women's Health - Meetings, 1992-1993 May (Box 9, Folder 49-50)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Fund Policies and Responsibilities, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 51)
  - Women's Health - Karen Davis - Appointments with Aides, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 52)
  - Women's Health - Senator Wellstone, 1993 (Box 9, Folder 53)
  - Women's Health - Senator Mikulski, 1993-1994 (Box 9, Folder 54-55)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Potential Members, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 56)
  - Women's Health Survey- Media Coverage, 1993 (Box 10, Folder 57-58)
  - Women's Health - WNET Documentary, 1992 (Box 10, Folder 59)
  - Women's Health Survey - Louis Harris and Associates, 1992-1993 (Box 10, Folder 60-61)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Planning Meeting, 1993 June 8 (Box 10, Folder 62)
  - Women's Health Survey - Questionnaire Construction, 1992 (Box 11, Folder 63)
  - Women's Health Survey - Questionnaire Drafts (Box 11, Folder 64-65)
  - Women's Health Survey - Meeting, 1992 November (Box 11, Folder 66)
  - Women's Health Survey - LHA Meeting, 1992 November 18 (Box 11, Folder 67)
  - Women's Health Survey - Questionnaire, Topics, Banners, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 68)
  - Women's Health Survey - Karen Davis - Comments, 1993 (Box 11, Folder 69)
  - Women's Health Survey - Experts - Meetings and Comments, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 70-71)
  - Baxter-LHA - Survey of American Health Habits (Box 12, Folder 72)
  - Women's Health Survey - Questionnaire Reviewers Comments, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Women's Health Survey - Additional Tabs (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Women's Health - Incoming Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 75)
  - Women's Health - McNeil - Early Correspondence, 1992-1993 (Box 12, Folder 76)
  - Women's Health Correspondence - Issue Papers (Box 13, Folder 77)
  - Women's Health Correspondence - Issue Papers - Rowland, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 78)
  - Women's Health Correspondence - Issue Papers - Stoiber, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 79)
  - Women's Health Correspondence - Issue Papers - Collins, 1992 (Box 13, Folder 80)
  - Women's Health Correspondence - Issue Papers (Box 13, Folder 81)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Issue Papers - Prevention, 1994 (Box 13, Folder 82-83)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Issue Papers - Mental Heath, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 84)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Issue Papers - Heath Care Reform, 1993-1995 (Box 14, Folder 85-86)
  - Commission on Women's Health (Grant 94-45) - Administrative, 1993 (Box 14, Folder 87)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Correspondence with Commissioners, 1994 (Box 14, Folder 88)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Management Meeting Notes, 1994-1995 (Box 14, Folder 89)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Management Meeting Notes (Mary Johnson), 1993-1995 (Box 15, Folder 90-91)
  - Commission on Women's Health - Management Meeting Notes, 1995-1997 (Box 15, Folder 92)